

# Soma Utsumi

## **Site Reliability Engineer**

Tokyo, Japan

qithub.com/soma00333

## **SUMMARY**

Senior Software Engineer with 6+ years and Site Reliability Engineer with 2+ years professional experience in Japan.

Engaged in the backend developments for enterprise SaaS and the design and operation of cloud infrastructures with high-security requirements.

## **SKILLS**

#### **SRE**

- SLI/SLO Design
- Postmortem
- Kubernetes
- Datadog

#### Platform Engineering

- Architectural Design
- Developer Experience
- Terraform

#### Cloud

- GCP
- AWS

#### Backend

- Go
- gRPC
- MySQL

## **LANGUAGES**

- Japanese(Native)
- English(Professional working)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2023-11 - Side, SRE in SRE desk

Present

enechain Corporation

- Lead creating manifest and terraform generator tools for developers that accelerate microservice development.
- Maintain and operate infrastructures centered on GKE.
- Lead designing teams and policies focused on governance and security.

2023-08 - Side, MLOps Engineer in LLM STUDIO

Present

Algomatic Inc.

- Lead creating learning infrastructures for LLM with AWS.
- Lead creating inference servers for LLM with AWS.
- Lead creating infrastructures for LLM applications with AWS.

2019-04 - **Co-founder,CTO** 

Present

Industry Technology Inc.

- Lead the backend development of enterprise SaaS with go, gRPC, and AWS.
- Lead migrating legacy Aurora Serverless v1 (MySQL 5.7) to Aurora serverless v2 (MySQL v8.0).
- Lead the creation of a company-wide security policy strategy.
- Lead getting logs and metrics, designing SLI/SLO, and setting appropriate dashboards and monitors on Datadog.

2018-04 - Data Analyst, Digital Marketer

2019-06

Gunosy Inc.

- Lead planning and applying A/B tests. Increase user retention by 30%.
- Analyzing the large-scale user data with MySQL and Redshift

2018-01 - Intern, Backend Engineer

2018-03

ZUU Co.,Ltd.

• Develop the internal system with Go

## **EDUCATION**

2014 - 2018

**Bachelor of Engineering** 

The University of Tokyo

Design of a preoperative evaluation system for elderly patients using a generalized linear model

## **DETAILED RESUME**

https://github.com/soma00333/resume/blob/main/README.md